How do you think, you as a bank
Как ты считаешь вот ты как банковский
employee Yes, that's interesting Yes, how do you
служащий Да вот это интересно Да как ты
think the key rate indicator is 21
считаешь показатель ключевой ставки 21
21 Yes, now, yes Yes, it just
21 Да сейчас да Да он просто каждый
changes almost every month Yes, how do you think
месяц почти меняется Да как ты считаешь
this is an indicator of improvement or
это показатель улучшения или
not, well, an improvement of what Well, the economy is even with the
нет ну улучшение чего Ну экономики с
pre-war
довоенным
Well, naturally, when the pre-war was
даже Ну естественно когда довоенное было
there 1011 cannot be compared Well, it is clear that it has
там 1011 не сравнится ну понятно что
become worse Again, how can it be better
стало хуже опять же как может быть лучше
With such a number of sanctions, with such a
При таком количестве санкций при такой
military burden, of course, it would be better not
нагрузки военной конечно лучше не бы
super
супер
Hello, and you are probably a
здравствуйте Здравствуйте а вы наверное
Streamer Yes, yes, I am a Streamer And you are probably a
Стример Да да я Стример А вы наверное
chat
чат
roulette I am probably just killing
рулеток Я наверное просто убивающий
time
время
here I realized
здесь понял
and that is the German flag in the background
а это на заднем фоне флаг Германии
Yes, you are in Germany Yes, I myself am
Да вы в Германии находитесь Да я сам
from Krasnodar But I have been living in Germany for 18 years
родом из Краснодара Но живу уже 18 лет в
in what city is
Германии в каком городе
Hamburg I understand, you
Гамбург Поня знаете
know Germany Well, I have never heard of such a city Well, shooting range Bern You know this I am fond of football and all this Dortmund Borussia Yes, I understand now, yes Bayern Munich Yes, not even conditionally ge No, well, I understand I understood yes That is, you are on football I think, as you know, yes  I
футболу Я же думаю как вы знаете да
see, it's interesting, yes, yes, I really
Понятно интересно да слу Мне как раз
like that even in the
очень нравится что у вас даже в
fourth division, stadiums for 40,000 people
четвёртом дивизионе стадионы по 40.000
gather here. Football is very popular.
собираются у нас футбол Очень популярный
Yes, football is popular, not like in Russia. It's
Да футбол популярный не так как в России
also popular in Russia. There is one team there,
В России тоже популярны в России вот там
for example, in Krasnodar. Yes,
есть вот у нас в Краснодаре условно Да
one team. And some are smaller. Well, there
одна команда А какие-то меньши уже Ну
used to be two. Well, that's it. Yes, that's it. And that's how it is with
раньше две был ну это такое уже
football in Russia now. I'm like this. Well,
России сейчас как с футболом я так Ну
they play by inertia because,
как они по инерции играют потому что ну
well, the Russian championship is held, but in
как бы чемпионат России проводится но по
fact, for what purpose if there are no European Cups, in
факту ради чего если еврокубков нет по
fact, only the Russian champion and everything
сути только чемпион России и всё всё
else. It's not so
остальное это не так
interesting.
интересно
Yes, you apparently support Ukraine.
да Ну вы видимо Украину да поддерживаете
Judging by the trident. Yes, it's a gift from my
Судя по трезубца Да это подарок моих
friends, and the cat is what it's
знакомых а кошечка это как это
called, a badger.
называется это барсук
Badger. And there, too, yes, there's a trident
барсук А там же тоже да вот это трезубец
hanging. A trident is a badger from a cartoon,
висит трезубец это барсук из мультфильма
and they just hung three teeth on it. I
а просто на него три зубчик повесили
understand. It's a leopard. In Germany, we have a
понят Это барс у нас в Германии есть
cartoon,
мультфильм
like, he's a military
типа он военный
badger. The Ministry of Defense removed
барсук Министерство обороны сняло
Hamburg. Well, I'm just in geography.  this is
Гамбург это ну я просто в географии это
West Germany and no no
Западная Германия и нет нет
Central Well when the Berlin
Центральная Ну вот когда берлинская
Wall was on which side in
стена была на какой стороне на
West Germany a small piece
Западно то Германии небольшой кусочек
was
был
u understood And your time is minus h Yes
у понят А у вас время ж минус ча Да
probably compared to c compared to
наверно по сравнению с с по сравнению с
Russia it's like Russia is very long Well
Россией это как Россия очень длинная Ну
with Moscow let's say with Moscow Yes one
с Москвой скажем с Москвой Да час
o'clock now Yes
сечас Да
2343 Listen you only years in Germany How would you not
2343 Слушай вы лько лет в Германии Як не
forget Look I'm 43 years old if I
забыли бы Смотри мне 43 года если я 25
lived 25 years in Russia and 18 in Germany how will
лет прожил в России и 18 в Германии как
you forget plus My parents are in
ты забудешь плюс У меня родители в
Krasnodar and in Germany Well as if there is
Краснодаре а в Германии Ну как бы есть с
someone to communicate with community Yes here
кем общаться коммьюнити Да тут
Russian-speaking people just
русскоязычных просто
Dafi understood Well and here now in roulette in
Дафи понял Ну а тут сейчас в рулетке в
this some specific topic you
этой какую-то определённую тему
communicate put the flag of Ukraine I communicate
общаетесь ставил флаг Украины я общаюсь
with Ukrainians and with Russians how they
с украинцами и с россиянами как они
see this war a
видят эту войну
Well God forbid that it will end soon right
а Ну дай Бог что это скоро закончится
now in Germany There is a gathering of
как раз сейчас в Германии Там сборище
all the powers that be in the world si just yes just you
всех сильных мира си как раз да как раз
see it will not end because Putin does not
видите не закончится потому что Путин не
want to sign peace agreements and
хочет подписывать мирные соглашения и
withdraw troops  from Ukraine So it won't
выводить войска из Украины Так что не
end No, I don't think there will be
закончится Да не я думаю в ближайшие 2-3
some kind of decision in the next 2-3 months in
месяца будет уже какое-то решение в
any case ka Well, I don't know in any
любом случае ка Ну не знаю в любом
case there will be some but
случае какое-то будет но
I think in the next 2-3 months it will displace Well, it's been
Я думаю за ближайшие 2-3 месяца вытеснит
6 months since they've been displacing 6 with pono
Ну так уже 6 месяцев вытесняют 6 с поно
Well, now there's already a turning point there's a turning
Ну сейчас уже там перелом
point we're looking at a turning point
намечается перелом смотрим
there's only this PTI
перелом там разве что этому ПТИ
anori let's see how it all goes for
анори посмотрим как оно всё будет для
me the most important thing is for it all to end as soon as possible
меня самое главное чтобы это поскорее
because I have
всё закончилось потому что у
All my relatives in Kyiv despite the fact that I
меня Вся родня в Киеве при том что я
live in Moscow and I just simply
живу в Москве и я просто Элементарно
want to go to the graves of my relatives no Will you
хочу на могилы своих родственников
come you won't come no
съездить не Приедете вы не приедете не
Well, when will it all end I think there are
Ну когда это всё закончится Я думаю
2527 citizens of Russia after the end of the war of course Well, I do
2527 после окончания войны конечно
n't know well take Here was the
Ну не знаю хорошо взять Вот была война
Second World War I don't think that
Вторая мировая Я не думаю что там надо
such a period of time had to pass there for them to
было такой срок чтобы прошёл чтобы там
return to their homeland not like that in the Second
вернулись на родину не так во Второй
World War the aggressor was defeated and defeated
мировой войне агрессора победили разгром
And Hitler's Germany ceased to
Да и гитлеровская Германия перестала
exist I don't think that now in the
существовать Я не думаю что сейчас за
next few years Moscow will be defeated like that As an
ближайшие годы так разгром Москву да Как
aggressor completely That is, it
агрессора полностью То есть это
will be
будет режим
pony regime So the Armed Forces I think the nearest
пони Так что ВС думаю ближайшие
agreements that will be they will not be in
соглашения которые будут они будут не в
favor of Ukraine Oh what's the point of Ukraine
пользу украи Ах смысл Украине
agreeing and you think they won't agree And
соглашаться а думаете не согласятся А
why well because Ukraine Ukraine I
зачем ну потому что Украина Украина
say the USA clearly Made it clear that they won't
говорю США явно Дали понять что не будут
continue this is all US prime And what's so special about the USA
дальше это всё Прим США А что США такого
giving Ukraine that it will support Degi
Дат Украине что она поддержит Деги
money Well the EU won't give
деньги Ну Евросоюз не будет давать
money if the US doesn't the EU
деньги если США не будет Евросоюз
on the contrary says Yes what well in
наоборот говорит Да что вот ну в
Germany we had this said today at the Minsk
Германии у нас же сегодня на Минской
conference yes everything is
конференции это говорили да всё
clear and the most important thing is look
однозначно и самое основное смотри
fairy tale for Russia This is
сказочка для Росси Вот это
Trump America to stop helping
трампом Америке переставать помогать
Ukraine Because it has its own
Украине Потому что у не есть свои
interests together with Putin What interests does
интересы вместе с Путиным Какие нарот у
America have to weaken Russia as
Америки интересы ослабить Россию
much as possible Trump when he came he clearly
максимально Трамп когда пришёл он явно
made it clear that Russia is not the
дал понять что Россия не является
main enemy in the Minsk
Главным противником в минских
agreements they said the same thing that everything is
соглашениях такое же говорили что всё
fine Yes in Istanbul they said that they
нормально Да в стамбульский говорили что
won't expand NATO to the east
не будут НАТО расширять на восток
true this is the Armed Forces it is clear this was back when the
правда это это ВС понятно это ещ когда
Soviet Union collapsed now also well what's
Советский Союз развалили сейчас также ну
the point look if for America eh Russia has
смысл смотри если для Америки э Россия
always been a strategic enemy of
всегда была стратегическим противником
America including in the Arctic Now
Америки в том числе и в Арктике Сейчас
yes they are preparing in the Arctic  to sort out a bunch of
да в Арктике готовятся разгребать куча
interesting things Yes, and for
всяких интересных вещей Да вот и для
Russia, oh, for America, the weakening of
России ой для Америки ослабление
Russia's military potential is just
военного потенциала России - это как раз
Bingo, the Russian army is dying now, yes,
Бинго армия России умирает сейчас да
technically, Russia is undermined, slapped with
технически Россия подорвана обложена
sanctions, cut off from European sales markets,
санкциями отрезана от европейских рынков
no gas, no oil, nothing, yes, that
сбыта всего ни газа ни нефти ничего да
is, Russia is really losing every single thing that
то есть Россия реально теряет каждый то
America invests in Ukraine, it's
что Америка вкладывает в Украину это
nothing compared to what its
мелочи по сравнению с тем что теряет её
enemy Russia is losing. Well, Russia has already managed to
противник Россия Ну Россия уже успела за
adapt over the years, it
эти годы приспособиться уже это первое
was hard at first,
время было тяжело
now how did it adapt, what was being built,
сейчас как приспособилась что строилось
where are you selling
куда вы продаёте
gas and oil, well, at the moment. It's just, in
газнефть ну вот на на данный момент Вот
my opinion, the day before yesterday. I read that the
как раз по-моему позавчера Я читал что
Turkish Stream has restarted its
по турецкому потоку опять запустилась
relationship, no, the Turkish
отношение нет
Stream is actually about
нет турецкий поток - это вообще-то про
gas and not about oil. Well, about gas, that's good.
Газ а не про нефть Ну про Газ хорошо
And no new gas is going there through the
Да и никакого нового газа там не идёт по
Turkish Stream. Well, okay, I just,
турецкому потоку Ну О'кей я я просто ну
well, if we abstract in
как бы если абстрагироваться вообще в
general from these military actions from
целом от вот этих военных действий от
everything, I can only judge from a domestic
всего Я могу судить только вот с бытовой
point of view. Yes, how am I doing? And the
точки зрения Да как мне живётся А я
only thing I felt on myself was that
единственное что на себе ощутил что
before I could go to Europe.  fly directly
раньше я мог в Европу лететь напрямую
now I can't do it directly I
сейчас я не могу это делать напрямую мне
need to do it with a transfer and
надо это делать с пересадкой и визу
open a visa in Serbia for me this is the
открывать в Сербии для меня это
only one that well for me it's not a
единственная которая ну для меня это не
problem because I can easily
проблема потому что я там спокойно могу
go to the same Thailand and Vietnam Well
поехать в тот же Таиланд и Вьетнам Ну
like instead of
как бы вместо
Europe everything else is okay there are no
Европы остальное всё ну О'кей нету
European cars China came Do
европейских машин пришли Китай
you think Chinese cars are better than
Как вы считаете китайские машины лучше
European ones I think not that is it has become
европейских Я думаю нет то есть стало
worse
хуже
so Well I'm telling you I can only
так Ну я же говорю я могу только к себе
judge myself I just have a car Well until
судить У меня просто машина Ну до сих
now Hyundai
пор Hyundai
Solar I don't know do you know such a car at all
Solar не знаю знаете такую вообще машину
No it's not me that's burning cars have become worse did I
Нет не я горю машины стали хуже я
hear correctly
правильно услышал
Well okay we are not taking purely my experience but we are
Ну хорошо мы берём не чисто мой опыт а
taking about Well yes Well of course yes cars have
берём об Ну да Ну конечно да машины
become worse in Russia so Well it seems to me
стали хуже в России так Ну мне кажется
yes cars are a hundred worse and more expensive so
да машины ста хуже и дороже так
super salaries in dollar equivalent have
супер зарплаты в долларом эквиваленте
become
стали
worse compared to what compared to the
хуже по сравнению с чем по сравнению с
pre-war
довоенным
period in dollar equivalent
периодом в долларовом эквиваленте
I would say that they are the same of course in 3
я бы сказал что такие же конечно за 3
years of war inflation ate these salaries
года войны инфляция съела эти зарплаты
but salaries remained at the same level at the
но зарплаты остались на том же уровне на
same
том же
level Well at least in dollars I
уровне Да ну как минимум в долла
wonder what
интересно Вы из какого
city are you from I'm from Moscow Moscow Yes how much does a
города Я из Москвы Москвы Да сколько
teacher in Moscow
учитель в Москве
get And I can directly  I need to name the exact amount
получает А я могу прям точную сумму
because I work in a bank and they
назвать потому что я работаю в банке и
actually come for a loan I see
собственно за кредитом приходят я вижу
and a teacher in Moscow gets 120,000 this is
а учитель в Москве получает 120.000 это
1200 120,000 This is definitely not a rate this is,
1200 120.000 Это точно не ставка это он
for example, he works one and a half or two rates
например полторы или две ставки
in Moscow Well, I can't
отрабатывает в Москве Ну я не могу
say I see two personal income taxes that they
сказать я вижу два НДФЛ которые
bring again let's do it this way Let's look at this
приносят ещё раз давай так Смотрим
vacancy for a teacher
так вакансия учителя
Moscow so here's an
Москва так
English teacher in a private
вот учитель английского языка в частный
kindergarten so and not this something is
детский сад так а не это что-то не то
wrong wait So in Moscow there are 80,000 rubles that's it I even just typed it into the Yandex search engine How much do teachers get in Moscow according to data as of January 1, 205, the average salary of teachers in Moscow is 109,800 average average And the median well
800 сред средняя А медианная
I didn't conduct such statistics
ну я не проводил такую статистику потому
because the average you know is taken into all these
что средняя это знаешь берётся в эти все
major ones in short and so on Yes I
мажорные короче и так дальше Да я
understand yes that the director gets 400 and
понимаю да что директор получает 400 а
the cleaning lady gets 50 No well we are not cleaning we are the
уборщица получает 50 Не ну мы не убор мы
logical composition of the berm I think that
логический состав берм Я думаю что
look 120 is  just
смотри 120 - это просто
Yes, I tell myself directly from my own experience,
Да я себе прямо из собственного опыта
here come teachers for a loan,
говорю вот приходят учителя за кредитом
they indicate
они указывают
120, once again I say if a person yes
120 ещё раз я же говорю если человек да
works two jobs, that is, in fact,
работает на две ставки то есть по сути
he works two jobs Yes, and of
он как работает на двух работах Да и шат
course, his income will be like that True,
конечно у него будет такой приход Правда
oh, that is, we say that you can
ой то есть мы же говорим оста по можно
work three shifts Yes, we
работать и в три смены Да ири
compare a normal teacher there
получать сравниваем учительницу там
and a teacher who solves
нормальную и учительницу которая реша
three times, but we take how much she gets on hand
три раза а вот берём сколько на руки
and not How much is her rate there That's
получает а не Сколько у неё там ставка
right, we look at how much on hand yes
Правильно мы смотрим сколько на руки да
in terms of the rate because Naru
в пересчёте на ставку потому что Нару
This is wrong, how wrong, look
Это неправильно как неправильно смотри
if, look, I'll explain if I work,
если смотри объясню если я работаю
for example, an eight-hour working day and
например восьмичасовой рабочий день и
if I work an hourly working day,
если я работаю часовой рабочий день
conditionally
условно да
yes Well, an hour in terms of an hour of work
Ну часо в пересчёте на час работы Вот
Now you
теперь ты меня
understand me No, well, let me give you another
понял Нет ну а давай я тебе другой
example, I work in Moscow I
пример приведу вот я работаю в Москве Я
work in a bank I have colleagues
работаю в банке есть у меня коллеги
who work in Smolensk, also in
которые работают в Смоленске также в
my bank My salary is much
моём же банке У меня оклад намного
higher than theirs According to our Employment
больше чем у них по нашему там Трудовому
Contract, the number of hours Nadina has,
договору количество часов у Надина
but my position implies
но моя должность подразумевает
constant overtime, that is  It seems
постоянные переработки то есть вроде бы
like on paper that I work 165 hours a
как по бумагам что я работаю 165 часов в
month that My colleague from Smolensk
месяц что Мой коллега из Смоленска
works 165 hours a month but I get paid
работает 165 часов в месяц но я получаю
twice as much Because I overwork somewhere one and
в два раза больше Потому что я где-то в
a half times more
полтора раза больше
So that's what I'm telling you
перерабатывают так вот Я же тебе говорю
So that's what I'm talking about In
так вот про что я говорю что в
reality, you need to look So a
реальности надо смотреть Да вот тебе
teacher came to the bank and She filed
пришла учительница в банк да Она подала
How much is her
Сколько у неё
income But
доходы да
you can't estimate it now That's why
ты ж не можешь оценить сейчас поэтому
she works two jobs That is, she's like she's working for
это она работает две ставки То есть она
two Yes, in fact, she's working Well that's all That's
и шат как за двух Да по сути она
why Yes And
отрабатывает Ну вот и всё Поэтому да А
look, your car, you have a new Lada,
смотри машина вот у вас Lada новая
how much does it cost now Well,
сколько стоит сейчас
how much does it cost I don't know The only thing I
а ну сколько стоит Не знаю единственное
saw is that Lada is now the only
увидел что Лада сейчас единственная
car that can be bought for up to a million
машина которая можно купить до миллиона
rubles Half a million It was Well,
рублей пол милна Она же была
just today I read the news
Ну вот буквально сегодня новость читал
that Lada is the only car left for up to a
что Лада осталась единственная машина до
million rubles But apparently some kind of
миллиона рублей но видимо какая-то
configuration where it's not an automatic, manual and there's
комплектация где не автомат ручной и там
another 10,000 dollars Do you think you can buy a
ещ 10.000 долларов Как ты считаешь за
normal European car for 10,000 dollars
10.000 долларов европейскую нормальную
Which Lado
машину можно купить лучше который Ладо
will be better Of course Yes, then where did you start living
будет конечно да то где же вы стали жить
better Well,
лучше
in cars  The Armed Forces are resting on cars, it's
Ну в машинах же ВС упирается в машинах
worse to live,
хуже жить
undercut, yes, Super, I got it, in what they started to live
подрез да Супер понял в чём стали жить
better,
лучше
then let's look at the apartments,
тогда давай по квартирам посмотрим
how much is your mortgage now,
сколько у вас сейчас ипотека
approximately?
приблизительно
And how much is what, mortgage, mortgage now, how much do you have, how much is it in percent
А сколько что ипотека ипотека сейчас
or what is the
сколько у вас сколько процентов или
amount and percentage? Well, a lot, a lot, that's how much, well, we do
какая сумма и процент Ну много много это
n't have any
сколько ну не есть у нас акции
subsidized shares at 6%, come on, come on,
субсидированные по 6% давай давай Так
how much is
сколько ипотека у
your mortgage? Well, let's take 24 24. You have a key
вас Ну возьмём 24 24 У вас же Ключевая
rate now of
ставка сейчас
21, yes. And by the way, today is
21 да А сегодня кстати сегодня 14
February 14. Today, there should have been a meeting
февраля Сегодня же должна была заседать
on the Bible, did they raise the key rate or not? They
на библи на подняли или нет ключевую
left it today, they left it because there was
ставку сегодня оставили оставили потому
nowhere to raise it. Yes, that is, look
что уже куда поднимать да то есть смотри
how you think, you, as a bank
как ты считаешь вот ты как банковский
employee. Yes, that's interesting. Yes, how do you
служащий Да вот это интересно Да как ты
think the key rate indicator is 21
считаешь показатель ключевой ставки 21
21, yes now. Yes,
21 да сейчас
it just changes almost every month.
Да оно Просто каждый месяц почти
Yes, how do you think this is an
меняется Да как ты считаешь это
indicator of improvement or
показатель улучшения или
not, an improvement of what. Well, the economy is with the
нет улучшение чего Ну экономики с
pre-war,
довоенным
yes. Well, naturally, when the pre-war was
да Ну естественно когда довоенное было
there, 1011 cannot be compared. Well, it's clear that it has
там 1011 не сравнится Ну понятно что
become worse, again, how can it be better?
стало хуже опять же как может быть лучше
With such a number of sanctions,  such a
При таком количестве санкций при такой
military load of course it would be better not
нагрузке военной конечно лучше не бы
super super you told me for 20 minutes
супер супер ты мне 20 минут рассказывал
how good it is And how it is better and now we have
как хорошо И как лучше а теперь мы
come to the number Wait wait you
пришли к числа Подожди подожди ты меня
won't catch me now by the tongue because I
сейчас не поймаешь за язык потому что я
said that I can only take From my
сказал что я могу брать только Из своего
experience from my experience I have not become worse at living
опыта из моего опыта я хуже не стал жить
because I have Well, purely on me
потому что у меня Ну вот чисто на меня
on my family these military actions have
на мою семью вот эти военные действия
not affected in any way in the worst direction
никак в хуши сторону не
I can only take from my
повлияли Я могу только брать своего
experience I can take from the experience of my friends
опыта я могу брать из опыта своих друзей
well how would they be who in principle plus or minus
ну как бы которые в принципе плюс-минус
there the income is the same as mine and well
там заработок такой же как у меня и ну
how would they be Let's do it again then look
как бы Давай так ещё раз значит смотри
let's do it for Russians cars have become less
давай так для россиян машины стали менее
accessible right Well this is for
доступными правильно Ну это к для
Russians housing has become less accessible
россиян жильё стало менее доступно
accessible Well not for everyone if there are children then
доступно Ну не для всех если есть дети
it is like this again once again look we we are
то оно такое ещё раз ещё раз смотри мы
talking when we talk for
мы ж говорим когда мы говорим для
Russians we are talking on average Yes it is clear that
россиян мы говорим среднем Да ясно что
someone can on average Yes someone
кто-то может среднем Да кто-то вообще
could even before this buy three apartments for themselves and not
мог и до это купить себе три хаты и не
worry yes that is for Russians cars have
париться да то есть для россиян машины
become less accessible housing has become less
стали менее доступны жильё стало менее
accessible Well what has happened  more accessible
доступно Да что ж стало более доступно
for
для
Russians it is necessary
россиян это надо
[laughter]
[смех]
so much that it has become more accessible
сильно что стало более доступно
I can't just say right away that it has
я не могу вот так вот прям сходу сказать
become more
что стало
accessible it is clear that everyone Also
доступнее понятно что все Тоже в
waiting for it all to end because
ожидании когда это всё закончится тому
even Elementary the same before YouTube and Instagram
что даже Элементарно тот же до YouTube и
banned on the territory of the Russian
запрещенный на территории Российской
Federation is
Федерации
sweaty YouTube and Instagram it was your
потно YouTube и Instagram это ж ваша же
government that
власть
banned it Yes it will not allow it from your
запретила Да она его не разрешит от тво
end of the war I think it will allow it so
окончание войны Я думаю разрешит так
look I just want to understand we
смотри Просто я хочу понять мы столько
talked so much How it got better how it didn't affect it is
общались Как лучше стало как не повлияло
interesting and then it turns out that cars are
интересно и тут оказывается по машинам
worse Yes, as a bank employee you
хуже Да ты как банковский служащий
understand that mortgages And in general and the
понимаешь что ипотека И вообще и
availability of credit in general and for the
доступность кредита вообще-то а для
economy yes you agree that for the
экономики да ты же согласен что для
economy the availability of
экономики доступность
credit money yes this is very-very important
кредитных денег да это очень-очень важно
but now you see due to the fact that the key is
но сейчас видишь за счёт того что ключ
very high due to this the deposits are very
очень высокий за счёт этого вклады очень
large I am sure that there are
большие таких вкладов я уверен что в
absolutely no such deposits anywhere in Europe look now
Европе нигде нет абсолютно смотри теперь
wait here's the trick I didn't
подожди вот в чём фишка Я же тоже не
do anything either Yes what do you get it
пальцем делал Да что у вас получается у
you get it that
вас получается что
now with such a key rate and such a
теперь при такой ключевой ставке и таких
level of deposits it makes no sense to bother and
уровня вкладов не имее смысла париться и
do some kind of business easier  put it on
делать какой-то бизнес проще положить на
deposit because you need to
депозит потому что тебе с бизнеса надо
recoup such profit from the business Yes, in order to
отбить такую прибыль Да чтобы
cover the deposit percentage, I
перекрыть процент депозита я правильно
understand correctly Well, you
же понимаю так Ну ты же
taught that it is much more difficult for new people to get into
учил намного сложнее новым влезть в
business, those who are in business now Especially
бизнес те кто сейчас в бизнесе Тем более
when all those who are there,
когда ушли вот эти вот все которые там
conditionally,
условно
mcd, left, they occupied all these niches Well,
mcd сним вот эти все ниши они заняли Ну
as if It is clear Who has a lot of money there,
как бы Понятно У кого там много денег
look That is, I mean, this is called
так смотри То есть я это же называется
stagflation, so when stagnation and
стагфляция так когда и стагнация и
inflation overlap You
инфляция накладываются друг на друга Ты
understand this You have a
же это понимаешь Ты же у тебя есть
specialized education, we are
профильное образование мы друг друга
very nice to each other Understood Look, it turns out
очень красиво Поняли смотри получается
that inflation is happening because the
что инфляция идёт из-за того что ээ
supply does not correspond to
предложение так не соответствуют
demand very much does not correspond there are no
спросу очень сильно не соответствует нет
goods, someone stopped producing
товаров кто-то их перестал производить
or importing them And so on, different reasons
или завозить И так дальше разные причи
Yeah, yeah, it turns out that other manufacturers And
Угу да получается другие производители И
so on Well, the owners of capital, it is
так дальше Ну собственники капитала им
easier for them to put it on deposit under conditional
проще положить на депозит под условные
20 How much is your
20 Сколько сейчас у вас
deposit now Well, I have it under 23 at 23 Yes,
депозит Ну у меня под 23 лежит по 23 Да
at 23, than bother turning over
вот по 23 чем ээ париться прокручивать
money to get 23 profit Yes, with
деньги чтобы получить 23 прибыли Да при
this  turbulence of the economy, that is,
э этой турбулентности экономики то есть
goods and services cost even less, so, so,
товаров и услуг стоит ещё меньше так То
it is still starting, but why did
есть это ещё запускается но из-за чего ж
Nabul raise the key rate,
ключевую ставку набуль поднимала вот
before the New Year, in fact, every
перед Новым годом по сути через каждые
month there, it was raised And that And now they would have
там месяц поднимала И то И сейчас бы
raised it simply politically, they raised it very much The
подняли просто политически подняли очень
cry there is that Nabiullina is deliberately
Крик там что Вот набиулина специально
raising it And so on, most likely,
поднимает И так дальше скорее всего
because of this, they did not raise it because the
из-за этого и не подняли потому что
economy is flying, the Armed Forces are the same as hell and they
экономика летит ВС равно в тартарары и
will raise it So, I think that now, at the
поднимать будут Вот я думаю что сейчас
beginning of March, they will raise it again because
начало марта будет снова поднимут потому
they were not
что дальше они же не просто так
going to do it for no reason Yes, well, I
собирались Да
think that no, why Well, because
вот Ну думаю что нет почему Ну потому
you saw the exchange rate and that the exchange rate Well, the exchange rate
что ты курс видел и что курс Ну курсу
is strongly strengthening the ruble Well, no, no,
идёт сильное укрепление рубля Так ту ж
stop, stop, no, it is not a question of the
не не стоп стоп стоп ту ж не вопрос в
exchange rate relative to the dollar, the question is
курсе относительно доллара тут вопрос в
about the purchasing power of this
том да о покупательной способности этого
ruble,
рубля ну
but now everything is very much
а сейчас вот как раз всё сильно
based on the fact that the population has a
упирается в то что у населения очень
lot of money in all the banks That is,
много денег лежит во всех банках То есть
now, roughly speaking, as soon as they lower this
сейчас грубо говоря как опустят эту
key rate, well, how do we hope Yes, there will
ключевую ставку сразу же Ну как Надеемся
be an opportunity to buy goods and
Да будет возможность покупать товары и
services, and all this money that is
услуги и вот эти все бабки которые
just lying in deposits, they  they will go to the
просто лежат на вкладах они пойдут на
market Come
рынок Давай давай значит
on then first of all they will lower the key rate and
во-первых тогда опустят ключевую ставку
even smiled really said
так и аж улыбнулся правда сказал
We hope you and I understand perfectly well
Надеемся мы с тобой прекрасно понимаем
as two economists Yes what no one now the
как два экономиста Да что никто сейчас
key rate in the foreseeable
ключевую ставку в ближайшем обозримом
future will not be there
будущем там не
it will be lowered in the second half of the twenty-
будет это во второй половине двадцать
fifth To what
пятого года будет опускаться До
price Well I well
скольки
how would I again I can only
Ну я ну как бы я опять же я могу только
from some of my own considerations I think
из какие-то свои соображения Я думаю
somewhere in July it will be around
где-то в июле будет в районе
15% cool interesting now look
15% прикольно интересно теперь смотри
how you think if all these depositors
как ты считаешь если все эти вкладчики
Yes they will run en masse to withdraw deposits from
Да массово побегут забирать вклады из
banks what will
банков что
happen Well it is clear
будет Ну понятно
that it will not be very good for the banking
что не очень будет для банковской
system that is so what will happen
системы это так так что
what are you hinting at default no no I am
будет что ты на дефолт намекаешь нене Я
asking what will happen That's what you think
спрашиваю что будет Вот как ты считаешь
I don't think that everyone will run No well
Я не думаю что прямо все побегут Не ну
you said that they will lower it and everyone will start
ты же сказал что опустят и все начнут
withdrawing and
забирать и
investing many who were waiting they
вкладывать многие которые ждали они
will wait and yes they will withdraw it is clear that for the
дождутся и да заберут понятно что для
country's economy this is not a very good
экономики страны это не очень хороший
option that is look what we are not
вариант то есть смотри мы что не
discussing everything turns out not a very
обсуждаем всё получается не очень
good option true
хороший вариант правда
therefore it is possible
потому можно
say in time maybe it's good it's
говори воно врем может быть хорошо
clear that all this is bad no so look it turns
понятно что это всё плохо нет так смотри
out that we are not discussing yes it
получается мы что не обсуждаем да
turns out that all the options are bad
Получается что все варианты плохие всё
anyway because yes you and here I absolutely
равно потому что да вы и тут абсолютно я
agree with you yes because in the kfi
с тобой согласен да потому что в той кфи
that is going on now and that is rushing Yes there is no
которая сейчас идёт и которая несётся Да
correct option we either try to
правильного варианта нет мы либо пробуем
fight inflation or try to
бороться с инфляцией либо пробуем
fight stagnation and
бороться с стагнации а
it really pushes the other into disarray that's
оно дове толкает другую в разнос вот
all Well yes Well what to do means to
всё Ну да Ну а что делать надо значит
end the military as soon as possible well
заканчивать как можно скорее военные ну
specifically the military operation
специально военную операцию
and look everything will become Well so look the
и глядишь станет всё Ну так вот смотри
question yes Question Uh how uh Well
вопрос да Вопрос Ээ как
in America If you and I understand all this so then the
ээ Ну в Америке Если мы с тобой понимаем
Americans are not stupid either They
так то американцы же тоже не дурные Они
understand Yes where is Russia rushing with such an
понимают Да куда несётся Россия с такой
economy
экономико
Why does America need to
Зачем Америке сейчас о мто
negotiate with Russia now about MTO It is
Договариваться с Россией
real well because apparently there are
реально ну потому что видимо есть
some of its own interests I think that it
какие-то свои интересы Я думаю что вот
seems to me that America is more afraid of
как мне кажется Америка больше боится не
China than Russia and they can conclude some kind of gentleman's agreement of their own
Россию а Китай и они могут какую-то свою
that conditionally let us decide something there on your terms you
что условно давайте мы на ваших условиях
give your word that
что-то там порешаем ам даёте слово что
you  there you will not do something with China Do
вы там не будете с Китаем что-то там в
you really think that someone
делать Ты реально считаешь что кто-то
listens to the word of
слушает слово
Russia
России
well let's say the word of Russia weighs more
ну скажем так слово России больше весит
than the word of Ukraine that What does the word
чем слово Украина та При чём тут слово
Ukraine have to do with it Ukraine is not a subject at all a
Украина Украина же вообще не субъект
subject of Russia and NATO in this Who
субъект России и НАТО в этом Вот кто
will take Russia's
будет России верить на
word for it Well Putin has already shown that Putin
слово Ну Путин уже показывал что Путину
can be trusted on the EU layer tomorrow
можно верить на сло ЕС завтра
teri party politics not in America Look
тери политика парти не в Америке Смотри
and in Europe we are all very pragmatic
и в Европе у нас все очень прагматичные
yes Russia had a huge military
да у России был огромный военный
potential left over from the Soviet Union
потенциал оставшийся от Советского Союза
huge Yes now we see yes all
огромнейший Да сейчас мы видим да все
these tanks armored personnel carriers all this aircraft they are
эти танки бтры весь этот там самолёт они
stupidly destroyed in Ukraine into nowhere I'm
тупо уничтожаются в Украине в никуда
disappearing All already how many guys There are there are they
пропадаю Всё уже сколько ребят Вот есть
showing damn nothing there on these on a
показывают блин не начем там на этих на
loaf they went into the attack
буханка ехали в атаку
because all the weapons have changed in general this
потому что изменилось вообще всё
whole potential
вооружение вот этот весь потенциал
that you say all was during the
который ты говоришь весь был во время
Soviet Union there were no drones which
Советского Союза не было Дронов которые
actually completely changed all this
собственно полностью поменяли всю Вот
combat
эту вот боевую
vehicle where is the Russian
машину где сейчас Флот Российской
Federation Navy in the Black Sea now Well again the question is
Федерации в Чёрном море Ну опять вопрос
at the bottom so
На дне так вот
look yes that is look for America for
смотри да то есть смотри для Америки для
America the movement of the Russian army is in
Америки жение армии России это на
Russia's favor  sanctions are clamped down on Russia, there
руку Россия санкциями зажата у России
is a crazy
идёт сумасшедшая
stockfish tightly Yes, from Gazprom energy resources,
стокфиш наглухо Да вот от энергоресурсов
they will raise the price of gas for you, I
Газпром будут у вас поднимают цену на
really cant say, I dont have gas anywhere Yes,
правда не могу сказать у меня газа нигде
everything for households will rise three times
нет Да что всё для домохозяйств три раза
already Yes And thats it, in short, everyone
уже поднимется Да И вот это короче все
who shouted We have cheap gas
кто кричали У нас у нас дешёвый газ
because Gazprom needs to somehow
потому что газпрому нужно как-то
compensate for its losses from the fact that
компенсировать свои убытки от того что
they disappeared, uh, the
они пропали
European sales market Where will they be from the
ээ рынок сбыта Европы Где будут с
domestic
внутреннего
market Okay, lets go So whats your forecast,
рынка О'кей давай Так какой твой прогноз
how and when will this all
как и когда это всё
end, my
закончится мой
forecast Well, okay, forecast Just what do you
прогноз Ну хорошо прогноз Просто как ты
think, my well, My estimate is somewhere
думаешь моя ну Моя оценка такая где-то в
around July 27, everything will already be finished, it will be done,
районе 27 июля всё будет уже закончено
they will be resettled there in Siberia, deep somewhere, the
их переселять там в Сибирь в глуб где-то
Russian Federation, yes, that is,
Российская Федерация да то есть вот это
on the territory of these regions, the
на территории этих областей Бут
militarized zone will be completely dismantled, all the
милитария зона полностью разберут все
factories there, any buildings will be
Там заводы любые постройки будут
dismantled and she will patrol
демонтированы и она будет патрулировать
under the blue helmets of the
под голубыми касками
UN Well, do
ООН
you really think that this Zokirova
Ну ты реально думае что вот эта зокирова
will be on the territory of Russia
будет на территории России
Well, look, on the territory of Ukraine, no Get it done,
Ну смотри на территории украи не Получи
Russia does not have  such a
сделать Россия не имеет такой
technical possibility to enter
технической возможности чтобы зайти в
Ukraine and do that there So that only
Украину и сделать там та Так что только
on the territory of Russia it will be possible to do
на территории России можно будет сделать
such Well, Russia wants to have a
такую Ну Россия же хочет типа иметь
buffer like over I dont think
буфер типа от над Я не думаю
that they will sign on these terms because
что подпишут на этих условиях потому что
everyone will say that this is a freeze of the
все будут говорить что это заморозка
conflict Ire 51
конфликта Ире 51
lept not Why slo Tom just so that
лепт не Почему сло Том как раз для того
it is not a freeze but not a
чтобы это было не заморозка а не было
burning yes it will be Here this
горящее да будет Вот сделана эта
demilitarized has been done as they do you think they will
демилитаризованная как они как думаешь
agree Well so you You probably did
договорятся Ну так ты Ты наверное меня
nt understand me again look Russia is withdrawing
не понял ещё раз смотри Россия выводит
its troops from the territory of Ukraine from Crimea
свои войска с территории Украины с Крыма
Donetsk Lugansk Zaporozhye region and
Донецка Луганска Запорожской области и
so on Further Yes And around the neighboring
так Дальше Да А вокруг сосед
lised Zone on the territory of the
лизированная Зона на территории
Russian
Российской
Federation now are you
Федерации вот сечас ты
serious And whats the joke from Kherson, it was
серьёзно А в чём прикол с Херсона же
withdrawn in any case no matter how
вывела при любом раскладе вот как бы
bad it was no matter what happened in this
плохо не было что бы не было в этой
military conflict Crimea
военном конфликте Крым
rr I think the agreement smo
рр я думаю договор смо
look look you If you are from Kursk from
смотри смотри вы Если вы из Курска со
your original territory which was
своей исконной территории которая была
not that Crimea You
не то что вот Крым Вы у Украины
seized from Ukraine but you did not seize Kursk from Ukraine
захватили а Курск вы Украины не
Here you had it And  when
захватывали Вот он у вас был И когда у
Kursk was taken away from you and you ran away from there
вас отжали курски и вы убежали оттуда то
then how will it differ from Crimea after all
чем тогда будут отличаться от Крыма всё
depends on military potential that's
же зависит от военного потенциала вот и
all if Ukraine knocks out of Crimea they will run away the
всё если Украина выбьет из Крыма убегут
same way as they ran away from Kursk
также само как и из Курска убежали
Well I don't know what will happen with Kursk there are
вот я не знаю как будет с Курском тут
two options either they will agree that
два варианта либо они договорятся что
Ukraine will withdraw its troops or they will have time before the
Украина выведет войска либо успеют до
signing of this agreement Well to
момента подписания этого договора Ну
force the Ukrainian troops to leave about to
заставить украинские воска выйти про
force me I am ready to bet just
заставить я го я готов поставить вот
anything that no matter how events
прям всё что угодно что как бы события
develop Crimea and the composition of Russia will never
не развивались Крым и состава России ни
leave this all this is already not that here
за что не выйдет это всё это уже
straight Well why look Why
ното вот пря Ну почему смотри Почему
just internal Confidence is like this well
просто внутренняя Уверенность вот такая
because well how why is it at
вот ну потому что ну как почему это на
the moment in all let's say
данный момент вот во всех скажем так
internal
внутренних
eh how to explain and inside each
э как объяснить а внутри каждого
Russian now there is complete confidence
россиянина сейчас это полная уверенность
that Crimea is Russia listen look another
что Крым - это Россия слушай смотри ещё
six months six months ago
полгода полгода назад
inside each Russian there was
в внутри каждого россиянина была
confidence that the Kursk region is an
уверенность что Курская область - это
untouchable territory of the Russian
неприкасаемая территория Российской
Federation there was such confidence Well yeah well
Федерации было такое уверенность Ну да
where is this
ну где Сейчас эта
confidence now this is a temporarily
уверенность на данный момент временно
occupied territory Look here is
оккупированная территория Смотри вот вот
all the confidence of the Russian Federation Here is the
вся уверенность Российской Федерации Вот
IS number  Kursk region Well, what kind of
номер ИС Курской области Ну что я такой
number can I do, damn, this is
номер за сся могу сделать бли не это
real from a real Cars of the Kursk region,
реально с реальной Тачки Курской области
that's all, now look at the question What are you
вот и всё теперь смотри вопрос Ты что
singing, you say in the middle of every
пой ты говоришь в середине у каждого
Russian that you will go to defend
россиянина что ты пойдёшь защищать
Crimea No, I won't go That's all it
Крым Нет не пойду Вот и всё оно в
will sit in the middle of you But no, I'm
середине тебя будет сидеть Но нет я тебе
telling you that the government will not
говорю о том что правительство этого Не
allow this Because there
допустит Потому что со стороны народа
will be too many questions from the people, look, for
будет слишком много вопросов смотри
example, there were questions from the people about
например со стороны народа были вопросы
why they left
почему ушли из
Kherson, no, there were, yes, Kherson was included in the
Херсона нет были да Херсон вписали в
Russian Federation, just like Crimea in the
Российскую Федерацию так же как и Крым в
constitution,
конституци
because the Armed Forces could not
уче потому что ВС военно не смогли
hold on militarily, they gave them a beating, that's all, let's do it
удержать дали звездюлей вот и всё давай
differently, you said you're streaming correctly Yes,
по-другому ты сказал стримишь правильно
you have a lot now It's already late at
Да много у тебя сечас Сейчас уже поздно
night, the 25th, look Well, come on, you
ночь 25 смотри Ну давай так вот ты
say they will sign on July 27th Come on, say that on the
говоришь 27 июля подпишут Вот
27th it
давай гово что 27
will be part of the Russian Federation,
и будет в составе Российской Федерации
nothing will change, I don't know, I have
ничего не изменится не знаю у меня вот
a feeling that July 27th is my birthday,
ощущение 27 июля у меня день рождения 27
July 27th It seems to me that everything will be super And
июля Мне кажется всё будет супер А
that's why Well, okay, are you ready
поэтому то Ну хорошо Ну ты готов
argue July 27 Well, here is your
поспорить 27 июля Ну ты же вот твоя
position against my position, I am sure that
позиция против моей позиции я уверен что
nothing will change and that's great. And I am sure
ничего не изменится и супер А я уверен
that it will change and that well, well, come on,
что изменится и что ну ну давай
well, because I am confident in my
вот ну потому что я уверен в своих
words. Why should I argue with you? I am an
словах Зачем че мне с тобой спорить Я
expert. I am an expert. I am telling you my
эксперт Я эксперт я тебе говорю свою
version. Okay. Well, you admit the
версию хорошо Ну хорошо ты допускаешь
possibility that you are wrong, of course.
такой вариант что ты ошибаешься конечно
Expert. I am an expert in that. My
Эксперт Я же в том Эксперт что есть моя
expertise may not correspond to
экспертиза она может не соответствовать
reality or there may be
действительности или может там
adjustments to the dates. I am
корректировки быть по датам я я я честно
telling you honestly. It seems to me that if the
тебе говорю мне кажется если пойдёт
question of Crimea comes up, then it will just be The
вопрос по Крыму то как раз уже будет
question of using nuclei. So stop, stop,
Вопрос использования ядер Так стоп стоп
stop, and why can't nuclear weapons be used
стоп а почему использование ядер нельзя
because of
из-за
Kursk. Well, because this is a question that, uh, not
Курска Ну потому что это вопрос который
hanging around now, in the sense that it is not
не не зависая сейчас в смысле не
critical. Look, this is the
критично Смотри это территория
original territory of the Russian Federation. Yes, they
Российской Федерации исконная Да на неё
found it. You yourself call it
нашли Её Ты же сам её называешь
occupied.
оккупированная
Well, temporarily occupied, yes, you
Ну Временно оккупированы да ты её
occupy it. That is, it turns out that according to your
оккупировать То есть получается у вас по
nuclear doctrine, a nuclear bomb can already be used. Well, this
ядерной доктрине уже можно применять
will be an escalation of the conflict. And
бомбу Ну это будет эскалация конфликта А
with Crimea, too, look again.
с Крымом также чем вот смотри ещё раз
Why, if Ukraine enters Crimea,
Почему если Украина заходит в Крым
Russia can  use a nuclear bomb in
Россия может применить ядерную бомбу
your opinion And for Kursk it can't that Kursk is
по-твоему А за Курск не может что Курск
worse than
хуже
Crimea No of course Kursk is not r So why
Крыма Нет конечно Курск не р Так почему
why Kursk doesn't defend
почему Курск не защищает
because because I don't know what to
потому что потому что я не знаю что тебе
answer you to your question but in fact I'm
ответить на твой вопрос но по факту Я
saying again and some of my own
вот говорю опять же и своих каких-то
internal ideas that it seems to me
внутренних представлений что мне кажется
Kursk is just like a flag that the
Курск - Это просто как флаг который
Russian government carries that here is a
правительство России вот несёт что вот
course not a course Crimea as a flag that Crimea is
курс не курс Крым как флаг что Крым вот
ours once and for all and that we are
он наш и раз и навсегда и что люте
always fierce but the course here is already a question Where were the
всегда а курс тут уже вопрос Куда были
funds spent on defense and on all that
потрачены средства на оборону и на все
Wait again Okay, do I
дела Подожди ещё раз Хорошо я правильно
understand correctly that if Ukraine comes and
понимаю что если Украина заходит
captures the Kursk region Bryansk and
захватывает курскую область брянскую и
Belgorod there will be no nuclear weapons And if it
Белгородскую ядер не будет И если она
captures Orel there will be no nuclear weapons If
захватывает Орёл ядер не будет если
Ukrainian troops stand near
украинские войска будут стоять под
Moscow there will be no nuclear weapons but if Crimea is
Москвой ядер не будет но если Крым будет
nuclear Did I understand correctly I can't
ядерка Я правильно понял я не могу
say how it will be Well I assume that
сказать как будет ну я предполагаю что
Crimea is well that's how our
Крым это ну вот как вот у нас
government likes to talk Yes about
правительство любит говорить да про
red lines or red lines Yes it
красные это красные линии ли Да вот мне
seems to me Crimea is just the last
кажется Крым - это вот прямо последняя
line that cannot be crossed
вот эта линия которую нельзя пересекать
I understood that is why that is Ukraine
я понял то есть почему то есть Украина
will capture Moscow but Crimea  will not touch yes no well
захватит Москву но Крым трогать не будет
Moscow is also one of the
да нет ну Москва - это тоже одна из
red lines yeah yeah and
красных линий ага а а
Peter Well and Peter is also the third red A
Питер Ну и Питер тоже третья крас А
prns B
прнс Б
got it Bryansk can be taken no again we'll
понял Брянск можно забирать нет опять же
take So before the
возьмём Так что до того как войска
Ukrainian troops invaded the territory of the Kursk
Украины вторглись на территорию Курской
region I thought that Kursk was
области Я думал что и Курск является
also one of the
тоже там одной из
lines there right look like well you were
линий правильно смотри как бы ну ты
right thinking Kursk was just a
правильно думал Курск это как раз была
red line the territory of the Russian
красная линия территория Российской
Federation you
Федерации
can go more than that Look now
можно да зайти больше того Смотри сейчас
foreign missiles are shelling the
иностранными ракетами обстреливают
territory of the Russian Federation and
территорию Российской Федерации и
nothing Yes yes although also in my opinion
ничего Да да хотя тоже по-моему
As far as I remember a year and a half ago it was
Насколько помню год полтора назад
said that the first missile was flying in
говорилось что первая ракета прилетает
We all think that this is involved in the
Всё мы считаем что это вовлечены в
conflict and a full participant in the conflict Well it's
конфликт и полный участник конфликта Ну
clear in k in Crimea they laid down the headquarters of the
понятно в к в Крыму сложили штаб
Black Sea Fleet They sank with British missiles
Черноморского флота Британскими ракетами
foreign missiles there
потопили иностранными ракетами там чуть
almost your entire fleet it has already
ли не весь ваш флот он уже куда-то
fled somewhere to Novorossiysk even further already in
убежал в Новороссийский ещё дальше уже в
Abkhazia they want to build there in
Абхазии хотят строить там в
Amchi this military port because they can
амчи военный этот порт потому что уже
even
даже до Новороссийска
reach Novorossiysk Well that is just you know I'll
достают Ну то есть просто сам знаешь я
say so until August 6 when Ukraine
скажу так до 6 августа когда Украина
entered  Kursk region for
зашла в курскую область для
me even mys we when I remember When in
меня даже мыс мы когда я пом Когда в
Belgorod region with RDC went and then
Белгородской обла с РДК заходил и то
officially it's like not ZSU but officially
официально это типа не зсу а официально
Russian volunteer corps there yes to
русский добровольческий корпус там да
probe like damn it's something
зондировать типа блин это что-то
unthinkable yes There are two villages there
немыслимое да Там два села там
Tavolzhanka something else Grayvoron it was
таволжанка что-то ещё Грайворон это было
and
а
now there damn two villages in Belgorod
сейчас там блин два села в Белгородской
region that's already part of Kursk region
области вот уже часть Курской области
stupidly and Russia did nothing they also
тупо и Россия ничего не сделала тоже
shouted everything now there will be a nuclear bomb
кричали все всё сейчас будет ядерка
nuclear now look and that's all Well
ядерка сейчас посмотрите и всё
again what demand do you have for the
Ну опять же сменя какой спрос яхо вот
sake of interest like you Russians how do you
ради интереса как вот вы россияне как ты
imagine a nuclear bomb what is a nuclear bomb and
представляешь ядерку что такое ядерка и
where it should fly to end the
куда она должна прилететь чтобы окончить
war well it should fly to Bankovskaya
войну ну она должна на банковскую
there is a nuclear bomb should fly to Kyiv
прилететь есть в Киев должна прилететь
Well to the center of
ядерная бомба Ну в центр
adoption
принятия
Ponya imagine
Поня представ
Prim if it flies there for example to
Прим если она там долетает например до
Kyiv and falls in the center of Kyiv How many
Киева да и в центр Киева падает Сколько
kilometers should this destruction
километров это разрушение должно
be I have an idea only at the
быть у меня представление только на
level of
уровне херосима
NASA's Herosim do I understand correctly that it is necessary to
НАСА я правильно понимаю что нужно там
destroy a couple of million
где-то там уничтожить там пару миллионов
Kyivans there for example well  how in your
киевлян так например ну как в твоих
eyes this nuclear bomb here it
глазах вот эта ядерная бомба вот она
fell how many people will die those those
упала Сколько это умрёт человек те те
more I will say in my eyes I ca
больше скажу в моих глазах я вообще это
nt even imagine it because I well as if
не представляю потому что я ну как бы
it doesnt sound funny Im from Kiev not
это не смешно не звучало я киевлянин не
so I understood then look the point is not that The point is that as
так я понял то смотри суть не в том Суть
you see well if
в том что как ты видишь ну если вот
Russia it went there Ukraine in Crimea
Россия она там всё зашла Украина в Крым
it releases a nuclear bomb it flies but the
она выпускает ядерную бомбу прилетает но
decision-making center is not in
центр принятия решения же не в
Kyiv And where in Brussels and in London
Киеве А где в Брюсселе и в Лондоне
Well no wait well and
Ну нет подожди ну а
Zelensky Zelensky is just a protg
Зеленский Зеленский просто ставленник
Talking
Говорящая
doll Well what
кукла Ну что
decider arent you afraid to
решае не боишься такое
say such things having a Ukrainian diaspora there
говорить имея украинскую там диаспору
next to the Great everything pova Well
рядом за Великого го все пова
yes the fact that everyone is
Ну да то что прямо за Зеленского все
ready to tear the last T-shirt on themselves right for Zelensky And
готовы последнюю майку на се порвать И
what will happen to me if I say something bad
что мне что-то будет если я скажу плохо
against Zelensky no Im not saying that
против Зеленского нет Я же не говорю что
something will happen Im asking you well like
что-то будет Я тебя спрашиваю ну как бы
this is
это
normal So wait again I
нормально Так подожди ещё раз я я
understand
понимаю
your fear that its
твою опасение что против главы
scary to say something against the head of state
государства страшно что-то говорить у
in your Russia e time Im those  I'll tell you a secret, I
вас в России е раз я те открою секрет
just hung up a German flag for the
это просто флаг Германии повесил для
stream. I'm from the city of Khmelnitsky and I live in the
стрима Я из города Хмельницкий и живу в
city of Khmelnitsky and now I
городе Хмельницке и сейчас в городе
'm in the city of Khmelnitsky. And tomorrow I'll be in the city of Khmeli
Хмельницке И завтра буду в городе хмели
and look, I can quietly so that the SBU doesn't
и смотри я могу тихо чтоб СБУ не
hear.
услышала
Zelensky.
Зеленский
Zelensky. If there's no one behind me tomorrow, I don't
Зеленский если за завтра за мной не я не
understand
понимаю что
what a noth is. I don't know
такое нот
what will happen to you
не знаю что с тобой будет
tomorrow. Apparently, nothing, what do you
завтра видимо ничего чего ты думаешь у
think, we don't think, no one can say
нас ничего думаешь у нас никто не может
anything against Putin, tell
против Путина что-то сказать скажи
Putin. And I don't think he's that understanding. The differences in the
Путину А я не считаю его таким понима в
World Cup are
ЧМ
that's the whole difference. I think
разни вот в чём вся разница Я считаю что
he's doing everything right. Look, cowards,
он всё правильно делает Смотри трусы
cowards, yes, you
трусы да
think everything was done correctly. Well, yes, there's
считаешь всё правильно делано Так ну да
no need for this war and so on and so forth, everything is so
не надо этой войны и так дальше так всё
bad now, no. I'm saying that there are clearly
плохо теперь нет я говорю что есть явно
some reasons that we can't
какие-то поводы которые мы не можем
know. Everything is not so
знать всё не так
simple. Everything is not so simple. Yes, yes, it's interesting. Well,
просто всё не так просто Да да Интересно
let's see. Are you a brave
Хорошо давай вот посмотрим или Ты смелый
person or a timid person? Who do
человек или несмелый
you think is to blame for the fact
Да как ты считаешь кто виноват в том
that now there is this big Key
что сейчас вот эта большая Ключевая
rate, expensive cars, and so on, who is to
ставка дорогие машины и так дальше кто
blame for all this?
виноват в этом всём
Well, that's the time. And the time  guilty No, but
Ну такое время А время виновато Не ну а
I have to name a specific person
я тебя должен конкретного человека
Well, a person, a group of people, who is to blame for the
назвать Ну человека группу людей кто
fact that the
виноват в том что такая
rate is so bad, that the economic situation is so
ставка что такая ситуация в экономике
bad, I dont know what to
плохая не знаю что тебе
[laughter]
[смех]
answer I looked at how you
ответить Я посмотрел как ты аж так
shrank from the thought that it was absolutely absolutely necessary, as I sat, so I sat Well,
сжался от мысли что надо абсолютно
who are you, citizens of Russia
сидел Ну кто же вот вы граждане России
Yes, look, your life has become worse, yes, your
Да смотрите вам стало жить хуже да у вас
cars have become more expensive, your mortgages are less accessible,
стали дороже машины менее доступны
more expensive, and so on And so on And you keep
дороже ипотека и так дальше Всё вы себе
asking yourself who is to blame for
задаёте вопрос кто виноват в
this, no, we dont ask, we understand that we
этом нет не задаём мы мы понимаем что
just need to wait a little bit and then it will be
просто надо подождать немного и дальше
[laughter] You
[смех]
know better, this is from the series how
лучше это знаешь вот из серии как мне
very Ravi to me when it first started Thats what
очень Рави когда только началось Вот это
everyone was saying, that you are cowards, that you do
со все говорили что вы трусы вы в Москве
nt go out in Moscow with
не выходите с
rallies, that you dont speak out, cowards Yes, you are
митингами что не выступаете трусы Да вы
cowards Well, listen to me Well, it
трусы Ну вот послушай меня Ну мы же
seems to me that I have never interrupted you,
вроде я ни разу тебя не перебивал
how much we talk there for more than an hour,
сколько мы общаемся там больше часа
probably, yes, I dont know Well, I interrupted And
наверное да я не знаю Ну я перебил И
what Well, this is a question of your upbringing Okay,
что Ну это вопрос твоего воспитания Окей
I was brought up that way
я так воспита
by right, I
по праву сильно
interrupt a lot, not badly, I was brought up by right, a lot, what the
перебиваю не плохо воспита по пра сильно
hell Well, what are you going to do to me, here I am  interrupted
ла Ну что ты мне сделаешь вот я перебил
And what will you do No I'm just
И что ты сделаешь Нет я тебе просто
pointing out to you that you're bad I'll
указываю о том что ты плохо я я буду
continue to be the same with you Well so what
дальше с тобой также ве Ну и что вот
look you're pointing out that it's bad and what am I saying
смотри ты ука что плохо и что я говорю
Yes and
Да и
what is it by right of the strong that I do this I
что вот по праву сильного я так я так
communicate this way and
общаюсь и
Yes being 1,000 klom with you of course I
Да находясь 1.000 клом у тебя конечно я
can't do anything to you everything Why are
тебе ничего не могу сделать всё Ты что ж
you complaining then I'm not complaining if you
ты жалуешься тогда не жалуюсь если
can't do anything World Cup I'm complaining I'm just
ничего не можешь ЧМ Я жалуюсь я просто
pointing out to you that you're poorly brought up
тебе указываю что ты плохо воспитан
Why And you confirm this Yes I
Зачем А ты это подтверждаешь Да я
confirm it brazenly brazenly confirm Yes
Подтверждаю нагло нагло подтверждают Да
I have such an upbringing and what Well nothing
такое у меня воспитание и что Ну ничего
your parents should just be
просто твоим родителям должно быть
ashamed Why aren't you ashamed they're proud of
стыдно Зачем не стыдно они горды за
me Well okay you see In short
меня Ну О'кей видишь Короче я я тебе про
what I'm telling you when it started And everyone
что говорю когда началось сво А все
said that you're cowards that you don't go out
говорили что вы трусы что вы не выходите
with rallies you're true Okay And now when
с митингами вы тру О'кей А сейчас когда
your country is being sold with all its
продаётся ваша страна со всеми полезными
minerals is
ископаемыми
being sold Well and how about 500 billion already
продаётся Ну а как на 500 млрд уже
said that we'll give you the minerals who
сказал что отдадим ископаемые вам кто
said well  your Great look today for
сказал ну ваш Великий смотри сегодня
example today they offered Zelensky
например сегодня предлагали зеленскому
to sign some kind of agreement he refused
подписать какой-то договор он отказался
he said we will not sign such a thing for us Yes
он сказал мы такое не подпишем нам Да
because he said that I need to
потому что он сказал что мне надо
first talk
сначала пообщаться
to Europe again Well of course yes this
с Европы ещё раз Ну конечно да это
Look these are our minerals and Yes and we are a
Смотри это наши ископаемы и Да и мы это
resource we will trade them super if
ресурс мы ими будем торговать супер если
there are absolutely look stop again
есть абсолютно смотри стоп ещё раз
look if there are companies that can
смотри если есть компании которые могут
come and develop this extraction
прийти и разрабатывать эту добычу
invest a lot of money super Let's do it this way there is no question of
вложить Кучу бабок супер Давайте так там
trade but there is a
не идёт вопрос о торговле а там идёт
question of how much money was invested in the
вопрос о том сколько бабок вложено в
war And that the money needs to be returned show show come on show
войну И что надо деньги возвращать
show the
покажи покажи давай покажи покажи
document What document I can only
документ Какой документ я те могу только
show Trump's words all all words
слова трампа показать всё всё слова
words can be shoved into one place look
слова можно засунуть в одно место смотри
if there is a document then we will say
если есть документ тогда будем говорить
Okay that's
О'кей вот и
all Well so that we can talk about some
всё Ну чтобы мы говорили о каких-то
Trump's words for example give him
слова трампа например отдать ему
Greenland resettle all the inhabitants of Gaza
гренландию переселить всех жителей газы
somewhere to another country Yes build up there
куда-то в другую страну Да там застроить
all this words this is all Conversations that's all
это всё слова это всё Разговоры вот и
I sko I How much Look as far as I can
всё я ско я Сколько Смотри я сколько
remember Russians they are all  3 years
помню россиян они все 3 года
full-scale All in short now
полномасштабные Всё короче сейчас
America will stop now America here
Америка перестанет сейчас Америка вот
Biden has already said that now just
байден уже то сказал теперь просто
Biden Replaced with Trump and that's it And they give us the
байден Заменил на Трамп и всё А нам как
same way they gave us look Trump has been here for
давали так и дают смотри Трамп пришёл
how long has he been and Ukraine is
уже сколько он да а Украине поставки
still receiving arms supplies They are going something he
оружия всё равно Идут что-то он там
is saying there and arms supplies are being sent by
рассказывает а поставки оружия идут
American missiles and then they end up on the
американскими ракетами ато концами по
territory of the Russian Federation They are beating They are beating The
территории Российской Федерации Бьют
American military will give they give
Бьют американские военные дадут дают
guidance on the coordinates of these objects they give
наводки координат на эти объекты дают
everything nothing has changed If
всё ничего не изменилось Если бы так
Trump wanted it that way he would have taken and stopped
Трамп хотел он бы взял бы и остановил
So you look okay let's do this about
Так что ты смотри хорошо давай это по
Crimea then we will argue
Крыму то будем спорить
No Why Well you are sure So why should
Нет Зачем Ну ты же уверен Так а зачем
I argue with you why should I argue Well
спорить с тобой мне зачем спорить Ну
the opportunity to win to prove Why the
возможность выиграть по доказать Зачем
right of the strong why why should I prove I
право сильного зачем зачем доказать Я
already by the right of the strong I know that I am
уже по праву сильного Я знаю что я
right why should I prove it to you
прав зачем мне тебе доказывать вот
look for example a
смотри например идёт
guy is walking down the street some guy runs up to him
ээ парень по улице подбегает к нему
Baby come on in short let's
какой-то Малыш давай короче давай
check like or like you are really
проверим типа или типа ты реально
stronger than me prove prove why do I need this
сильнее меня докажи докажи зачем мне это
baby goes on Here is the dish why do I need it that is you
малыш идёт дальше Вот яство зачем мне то
need this you want something I do
есть тебе нужно это ты что-то хочешь Мне
n't need it
это не нужно
No I am just so much  I'm sure of myself that
Нет я просто настолько уверен в себе что
I want to get a win from you why do I need
я хочу да получить от тебя выигрыш зачем
this look Why do I need to play with you well you
мне это смотри Зачем мне с тобой играть
you If you are sure of your words you will
ну ты ты Если уверен в своих словах ты
get a win from me Why do I
получишь от меня выигрыш Зачем мне твой
need your win I don't need it why Well how why do I need to play with you
выигрыш я не нужен зачем Ну как зачем
at all it's your business I am my business to offer
вообще дело твоё Я моё дело предложить
I am an adult self-sufficient
я взрослы Я взрослый самодостаточный
person Why do I need to play with you Who are you
человек Зачем мне с тобой играть Кто ты
anyway Well who are you to make it interesting to play with you
вообще Ну кто ты чтобы с тобой играть
Well don't hang
интересно было Ну не Зависай
please the game
пожалуйста игра
[music]
[музыка]
broke down hung that's
сорвалась завис
how everything is in Russia Everything is good everything nothing has
вот так всё в России Всё хорошо всё
changed cars Yes yes less
ничего не изменилось машины Дада менее
accessible mortgages this that that And what that
доступны ипотека то то то А что что
has become more accessible I won't say that that's
стало более доступно я так не скажу вот
all all Russians they live fairy tales
и всё все россияне они живут сказками
live fairy tales that everything is good Everything is
живут сказками о том что Всё хорошо Всё
better yes but everyone understands that it is getting worse and worse
лучше да но все понимают что хуже и хуже
and worse and everyone lives in the hope that now
и хуже и все живут надеждой что сейчас
some white gentleman from America will
какой-то белый Господин из Америки всё
sort everything out then Biden should have sorted it out
разрулит то байден должен был разрулить
now
теперь
Trump everything will be very transparent Yes everything will
Трамп всё будет очень прозрачно Да всё
go on as usual Russia
будет идти своим чередом Россия
physically cannot return Kursk it
физически Курск не может вернуть не
cannot for six months and these funny ones if
может полгода и вот эти смешные вот если
Crimea is nuclear
Крым будет ядерка
nuclear will be A  here is Kursk Well Kursk And where is
ядерка будет А вот Курск Ну Курск А где
Kursk yesterday he was on the stream Yes the kid didn't
Курск вчера он на стриме Да пацанчик
even know that Kursk is a
вообще не знал что Курск - это
Russian region thought it was
российская область думал это
Ukrainian that's
украинская вот и
all nothing Russia can't Ukraine is
всё ничего Россия не мо жат Украина
now stronger than 3 years ago
сейчас сильнее чем 3 года назад Вот эти
All these fables damn Trump there 500 billion damn
все басни блин Трамп там 500 млрд блин
Trump he spoke Greenland Canada
Трамп он гренландию Канаду говорил
in short there gas damn this guy is a generator of
короче там газу блин это чувак генератор
all sorts of ideas all sorts of ideas Or maybe
просто всяких идей всяких идей А може
about Ka it didn't work Okay I'll
про Ка не прокатила Окей я
try and the fact that Russians are all hoping
попробую и то что россияне все надеятся
for Trump this shows that Russia
на трампа это показывает что Россия не
cannot get its territories back by military means
может вернуть свои территории военным
Russia can't Otherwise it would have returned
путём Россия не может Иначе она вернула
from a position of strength would have talked to
из позиции силы бы разговаривала под
Kyiv would have gone in with troops and that would have been it the
Киев зашла войсками бы и всё бы цент
decision-making center they
принятия решений они
can so like the video like a squeak
могут так что лайк
comment and send this
катра лайк писка комент и скиньте Цей
video all the way Glory to Ukraine write on
видос всм ё Слава Украине пись на й
Instagram I don't know why this is for you
Instagram Я не знаю для чого це тоб для
why else you can watch it on the office But for
чого ще тоб там дивитись на офес Але для
you this is one, two or three clicks  But you
тебе це оди два або три клика Але ты
try me and I will be KTA in me there is Kupa
тримае мене и я буду КТА в мене там Купа
Flo and in me there will be a cool mood to
Фло и в мене буде класный настр щоб
do but cool video letter on Instagram
робити но крут вдео пись на й Instagram
Popik Andriy
Попик Андрий
then Come on I'm
отак Давай я тебя
waiting for you N
чекаю N